#### ANGELA CASTILLO-GILL

Phone: +34 683666187, E-mail: acastillogill@gmail.com

I am a data analyst training to become a data scientist. Currently working with large public datasets applying statistical analyses to visualise findings and reveal insights. My degree in industrial engineering has given me the skills to use new techniques in the field of marketing, consumer research, predictive analytics and machine learning. Having worked in a marketing environment and written reports to present complex information in simple terms, I have developed great verbal and written communication skills. With a keen eye for detail, strong numeracy and problem-solving skills, I have learnt quickly in a fast-paced environment. I am fluent in the R programming language and have essential knowledge of SQL, and Google Analytics.

Available from February 2019 for roles based in London or Greater London.

#### DATA ANALYSIS SKILLSET

Languages	Machine learning	Data Viz tools	Libraries	Maths
-R (fluent)	-Linear regression	-Excel	-Dplyr	-Linear algebra
-SQL (essential)	-Logistic regression	-Google Charts	-Ggplot2	-Multivariate calculus
	-PCA	-Canva	-DataTable	-Probability distributions
	-K-Means clustering	-Tableau	-mlr	-Bayes theorem
	-CART		-Caret	-Correlation
	-Random Forests		-Gbm	-Hypothesis testing
	-k-Nearest Neighbors		-XGBoost	

#### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# UNIVERSITAT AUTÒNOMA DE BARCELONA Barcelona, Spain

Researcher

Mar 2017 - Present

- Compiled 160+ records from a wide range of sources (e.g. archives, interviews, databases) to build a spatial dataset of invasive species for the Iberian Peninsula.
- Estimated hundreds of thousands of euros in expenditures that led to the evaluation of a public policy for Catalonia in partnership with the Idealista S.A. data team. Idealista is a digital company that offers a marketplace for property in Spain and Italy.
- Wrote an original research article currently in the last stages of revision for submission to the peer-reviewed journal Ecological Economics with the collaboration of local Government authorities.
- Presented research findings at three conferences (British Ecological Society, ICTA Spring Symposium, International Symposium on Ecological Economics) to support the internalisation of the institute.
- Designed a model to simulate the behaviour of over 7,000 trees under uncertain conditions to run an invasion model using R.
- Visualised over 18 years of tree stocks in Catalonia to understand the spatial dynamics and design more robust public policies.

# INFORMA London, United Kingdom

Consultant

- Researched three original content reports for Informa's Agribusiness Intelligence (each one over 100 pages): 1. Quinoa Markets 2016 Trends and Opportunities, 2. Colombian Agribusiness after FARC peace deals, and 3. Delivering the Sustainable Development Goals
- Negotiated the content of the three published reports.
- Wrote all three reports, each over 100 pages each.

(SDGs) in Agrifood Companies 2017

- Produced the marketing material used to promote the reports.
- Designed and proofed the total 12 chapters of content.
- Delivered the reports on time with a high level of professionalism.

Apr 2016 – Mar 2017

# UNIVERSIDAD SERGIO ARBOLEDA

#### Bogotá, Colombia

Lecturer

- Designed the module Best Practices in Cleaner Production geared towards last year Industrial Engineering Students.
- Taught the module to a class of 30 students to encourage implementation of Environmental Management Systems in Colombia.
- Motivated the implementation of Best Practices in Cleaner Production in 5 small and medium sized enterprises (SME's) in Bogotá, Colombia.
- Led the students towards the successful completion of the module using a mix of hands-on activities including real case studies.
- Created the capstone project that allowed students to put their learning into real-world practice.
- Evaluated the students' progress throughout the course and provided feedback to allow them to understand how they could improve.

## HRA FOOD AND DRINK

Oct 2015 - Jan 2016

Aug 2016 - Dec 2016

# Torquay, United Kingdom

Researcher and Analyst

- Analysed every aspect of the UK flavoured milk industry including main producers, brands, formulas, consumer trends, packaging and distribution.
- Diagnosed challenges and opportunities for the dairy industry in response to recently introduced regulation like the 2018 sugar tax.
- Suggested innovation strategies for the dairy industry and niche food markets in the United Kingdom.
- Wrote 2 reports for the British flavoured-milk industry that included consolidated trends and suggested growth areas.
- -Represented the company at national-level events including Food Matters Live.

## **EDUCATION**

# UNIVERSITY OF EXETER, Master of Science in Food Security & Sustainable Agriculture Exeter, United Kingdom – Grade: Distinction Award Research project: Did weather cause the 2008-2011 coffee leaf rust outbreak in Colombia? UNIVERSIDAD DE LOS ANDES, Bachelor of Science in Industrial Engineering Bogotá, Colombia – Grade: 4.02/5 (top 10% of cohort) Key modules: Probability and Statistics, Optimization, Finances, Logistics, Organizations.

# **GRANTS AND AWARDS**

María de Maetzu

Spanish Ministry of Economy and Competitiveness (MINECO)

Awarded a scholarship worth €50,000 to pursue a María de Maetzu PhD. 'María de Maeztu' Unit of

Excellence is the highest institutional recognition of scientific research in Spain.

IBM, United Kingdom
2015

IBM Best Student Recognition Event 2015

Awarded a place at the IBM Best Student Recognition Event in Amsterdam, Netherlands.

# **UNIVERSITY OF EXETER, United Kingdom**

2014

Ayudar Scholarship

Awarded £30,000 to fund tuition and maintenance fees during postgraduate studies.

#### LANGUAGE SKILLS

English (native), Spanish (native) and French (intermediate).